Guide to the Lloyd Richards Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Professional Papers, 1966-2002; Series II; 26.8; (39 boxes)
  - Speeches and Lectures
    - University of California, San Diego "Cultural Diversity in the American Theatre" Conference, 1990 November (Box 67, Folder 806)
    - Walter Kerr Theatre Opening, 1990 March (Box 67, Folder 807)
    - Nelson White memorial service, 1990 January (Box 67, Folder 808)
    - Williams College, 1992 November (Box 67, Folder 809)
    - Yale University
      - 1981 (Box 67, Folder 810)
      - 1982 (Box 67, Folder 811-812)
      - 1983 (Box 67, Folder 813-816)
      - 1984 (Box 67, Folder 817-819)
        Includes Ed Cole tribute
      - 1985 (Box 68, Folder 820-824)
        Includes Cole Porter tribute
      - 1986 (Box 68, Folder 825-827)
        Includes Stanley Kaufman tribute
      - 1987 (Box 68, Folder 828-831)
      - 1988 (Box 69, Folder 832-834)
      - 1989 (Box 69, Folder 835-839)
      - 1990 (Box 69, Folder 840-843)
      - 1991 (Box 69, Folder 844-845)
    - Yale University "Telecommunications and the Performing Arts" symposium and unidentified symposium, 1982, 1984 (Box 69, Folder 846)
      Includes research articles
    - Peter Zeisler tribute, 1995 June (Box 70, Folder 847)
      Theatre Communications Group
    - Poetry readings given by Richards, undated (Box 70, Folder 848)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 70, Folder 849)
      Includes 1955 clippings
    - Statement on television program "New in New York", 1984 December (Box 70, Folder 850)
  - Awards and Honorary Degrees
    This subseries is organized under headings for certificates and plaques and objects.
    - Certificates
      - 1962-1991 (Box 71, Folder 851-876)
      - 1991-1998 (Box 72, Folder 877-887)
      - "A Salute to Lloyd Richards" event in celebration of Richards's retirement from Yale University on May 13, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 888-892)
        Includes book of contacts for invitations and printed material
      - "Tribute to Lloyd Richards: The Man and his Work" at Yale University on October 20, 1998
        Book of printed material, correspondence and photographs
    - Plaques and objects
      Arranged by size and weight
      - 1982-1995 (Box 73)
      - 1987-2003 (Box 74)
      - 1992, 2001-2006 (Box 75)
      - 1993, undated (Box 76)
      - 1965, 1979, 1988-2001 (Box 77)
      - 1980, 1985-1991, 2000, undated (Box 78)
  - Subject Files
    - "Black studies", 1977 (Box 79, Folder 893)
      Includes letters from Errol Hill on materials
    - "Chekhov lecture", undated (Box 79, Folder 894)
    - "Hate", 1991-1995 (Box 79, Folder 895)
    - Al Hirschfield, 2001 (Box 79, Folder 896)
    - Kadmus International Cultural Center for Research and Development, undated (Box 79, Folder 897)
    - "LIFE reference", undated (Box 79, Folder 898)
    - "New York City", 1992 (Box 79, Folder 899)
    - "Nikos", 1989 (Box 79, Folder 900)
    - "Obscenity in the arts", 1989 (Box 79, Folder 901)
    - "Quotes", undated (Box 79, Folder 902)
      Includes Richards quotes
    - "Shakespeare quotes", undated (Box 79, Folder 903)
    - "Soviet Artists", undated (Box 79, Folder 904)
    - "World's Great Religions", undated (Box 79, Folder 905)
  - Other Papers
    - Writings by Lloyd Richards
      - "Modest Ecstacies" in American Theatre, 1986 September (Box 80, Folder 906)
    - Interviews
      - With Richards by Michael Bertin, 1979 July 19 (Box 80, Folder 907)
      - With Richards by Chris Haines, 1998 March 19 (Box 80, Folder 908)
      - With Richards by Hall of Arts, 1991 February 15 (Box 80, Folder 909)
      - "Notes from the Master" by Mikell Pinkney, 1997 Spring (Box 80, Folder 910)
        Includes letter from Pinkney to Richards
      - With Richards by Sandra G. Shannon, 2000 June 1 (Box 80, Folder 911)
        Includes letter from Shannon to Richards
      - With Richards by Caroline Raymond, 2002 March 26 and April 3 (Box 80, Folder 912)
      - With Woodie King, Jr. by Richards in celebration of New Federal's 30th Anniversary in Theatre Development Fund Sightlines, 2000 June 1 (Box 80, Folder 913)
    - Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 80, Folder 914-919)
    - Illustrations of various people, including Richards, 1991
    - Writings of Others
      - "Theatre in Yorubaland" by Michael James Etherton, 1997 September (Box 80, Folder 920)
      - Various speeches for Tommy Hollis memorial service, 2001 November (Box 80, Folder 921)
    - Agendas
      - 1960-1970 (Box 81, Folder 922-931)
      - 1971-1983 (Box 82, Folder 932-944)
      - 1984-1992, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 945-954)
      - 1991-2006 (Box 84, Folder 955-961)
    - Address books, undated (Box 84, Folder 962)
    - Rolodex, undated (Box 85)
    - Rolodex, undated (Box 86)
    - Publicity on Richards, 1952-2006, undated (Box 87, Folder 963-1020)
    - Publicity on Richards and others
      - Athol Fugard (Box 88, Folder 1021-1024)
      - August Wilson (Box 88, Folder 1025-1029)
      - Various articles (Box 88, Folder 1030-1049)
  - Programs
    These programs are for productions that Richards had no involvement in and are arranged alphabetically by title.
    - A-G (Box 89, Folder 1050-1068)
    - H-R (Box 90, Folder 1069-1087)
    - R-Z, unsorted (Box 91, Folder 1088-1104)
    - Unsorted (Box 92, Folder 1105-1115)
- Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center, 1965-2001; Series III; 16.39; (38 boxes)
  Series III. Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center is organized into two subseries: National Playwrights Conference and General Files.
  This series contains material documenting the general activities of the Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center and more specifically its annual National Playwrights Conference, for which Richards was Artistic Director.
  The National Playwrights Conference subseries includes material compiled by the O'Neill Center administrative staff and contains files regarding planning and executing the annual National Playwrights Conferences. These materials include programs, catalogues, project files, cast lists, selection materials, evaluations, contracts, contact lists, copies of "The Scene" newsletter, financial documents, correspondence, photographs, reports, equipment lists and plans, critique notes, grant information, and publicity material. Materials in this subseries under the headings General Files and Binders are similar to each other.
  The subseries General Files contains printed material, correspondence, financial documents, and other papers that relate to proceedings and projects of the Center.
  Nearly all photographs in this subseries were taken by A. Vincent Scarano, the National Playwrights Conference photographer.
  Additional photographs can be found in Series V. Photographs.
  - National Playwrights Conference
    The subseries is organized under six headings: General Files, Correspondence, Binders, Playbills and Programs, Photographs, and Publicity.
    - General files
      Apart from files listed by subject at the end of the subseries, these files are arranged chronologically.
      - 1965-1999, undated, 1965-1979 (Box 93, Folder 1116-1133)
      - 1979-1987 (Box 94, Folder 1134-1146)
      - 1987-1999, undated (Box 95, Folder 1147-1164)
      - List of black playwrights, 1969-1971 (Box 96, Folder 1165)
      - Harold and Mimi Steinberg Charitable Trust and Prize, 1996-1999 (Box 96, Folder 1166-1167)
      - Czech collaboration, 1993 (Box 96, Folder 1168)
      - Finland collaboration, 1993-1995 (Box 96, Folder 1169)
      - Jo Henderson memorial, 1988 (Box 96, Folder 1170)
      - Edith Oliver Fellows Award, 1994 (Box 96, Folder 1171)
      - "Remembering Edith Oliver" memorial tribute, 1998 July 19 (Box 96, Folder 1172-1173)
        Includes Richards's speech
      - Wole Soyinka's visit and production of Madmen and Specialists, 1970-1973 (Box 96, Folder 1174)
      - Contract between National Playwrights Conference and American Broadcasting Company, 1977, 1981 (Box 96, Folder 1175)
      - Ink drawings of the O'Neill Center by Carolyn Lee Parmer-Klein Schwartz, 1991 (Box 96, Folder 1176)
    - Correspondence
      - Thank you notes
        - 1979 (Box 97, Folder 1177)
        - 1981 (Box 97, Folder 1178)
        - 1986 (Box 97, Folder 1179)
        - 1997 (Box 97, Folder 1180-1181)
        - 1998 (Box 97, Folder 1182-1183)
      - General, 1980-1994 (Box 97, Folder 1184)
      - With and regarding Eugenia and Ira Hauptman, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 1185)
      - Regarding retirement, 1999 (Box 97, Folder 1186)
    - Binders
      All binders were disassembled by library staff during processing.
      - 1965-1978 (Box 98, Folder 1187-1192)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 99, Folder 1193-1199)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 100, Folder 1200-1206)
      - 1982-1985 (Box 101, Folder 1207-1213)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 102, Folder 1214-1219)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 103, Folder 1220-1225)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 104, Folder 1226-1231)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 105, Folder 1232-1237)
      - 1989 (Box 106, Folder 1238-1243)
      - 1990 (Box 107, Folder 1244-1248)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 108, Folder 1249-1255)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 109, Folder 1256-1261)
      - 1993-1993/1994 (Box 110, Folder 1262-1266)
      - 1993/1994-1995, 1993-1995 (Box 111, Folder 1267-1273)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 112, Folder 1274-1278)
      - 1997 (Box 113, Folder 1279-1285)
        1997 binder contains material regarding Two Trains Running 1990 production at Yale Repertory Theatre
      - 1998 (Box 114, Folder 1286-1289)
      - 1999, undated (Box 115, Folder 1290-1295)
      - "The National Playwrights Conference 1965-1972, A Report" (Box 115, Folder 1296)
      - National Playwrights Conference: A brief history of playwrights and plays developed at The National Playwrights Conference: 1966-1997 (Box 115, Folder 1297)
    - Playbills and Programs, 1984-1999 (Box 116, Folder 1298-1301)
    - Photographs
      - 1965-1981 (Box 117, Folder 1302-1318)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 118, Folder 1319-1332)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 119, Folder 1333-1346)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 120, Folder 1347-1360)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 121, Folder 1361-1372)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 122, Folder 1373-1385)
      - 1990-1992 (Box 123, Folder 1386-1411)
      - 1992-1994 (Box 124, Folder 1412-1426)
      - 1994-1996 (Box 125, Folder 1427-1434)
      - 1996-1998 (Box 126, Folder 1435-1440)
      - 1998-1999, undated (Box 127, Folder 1441-1447)
      - Of Harold Clurman, undated, 1983 (Box 127, Folder 1448)
        Includes program for May 1983 "The Harold Clurman Professorship"
      - Of Edith Oliver, undated (Box 128, Folder 1449)
      - Of Edith Oliver remembrance service, 1998 (Box 128, Folder 1450)
      - Of August Wilson and production of Seven Guitars, 1995 (Box 128, Folder 1451)
      - "Mr. Gerald Fraser and Clara Rotter, New York Times", undated (Box 128, Folder 1452)
      - Various, undated (Box 128, Folder 1453)
        Includes photographs of August Wilson
      - Framed photograph, undated (Box 128, Folder 1454)
    - Publicity, 1971-1997
  - General Files
    - American Soviet Theatre Initiative, 1987-1988, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 1455)
    - Board reorganization, 1979 (Box 129, Folder 1456)
    - Contact books, 1992-2000 (Box 129, Folder 1457)
    - Designers, undated (Box 129, Folder 1458)
    - Dorothy Fields typescript writing on being a playwright at the O'Neill Center, 1982 (Box 129, Folder 1459)
    - Financial, 1979-1982 (Box 129, Folder 1460-1462)
    - Five Year Plan, 1986 (Box 129, Folder 1463)
    - Fundraising, 1997-1998 (Box 129, Folder 1464-1465)
    - General information, 1976 (Box 129, Folder 1466)
    - Jerome Foundation, 1986, 1991 (Box 129, Folder 1467)
    - National Corporate Theatre Fund, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 1468)
    - National Theatre of the Deaf, 1981 (Box 129, Folder 1469)
    - Eugene O'Neill postage stamp "First Day of Issue Ceremonies", 1967 (Box 129, Folder 1470)
    - Reports, 1981 (Box 129, Folder 1471)
    - Russian trip and relationship with Russian playwrights, 1982 (Box 130, Folder 1472-1474)
    - Simsbury Fund, 1979 (Box 130, Folder 1475)
    - Strategic Planning Committee, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 1476)
    - "Celebrating George C. White," October 2001 event planning and material regarding new director (Box 130, Folder 1477)
      Includes letter from Richards to Howard Sherman, executive director of the O'Neill Theater Center, about including National Playwrights Conference records in Richards's personal archive. Includes "The Eugene O'Neill Theater Center: The First Five Years 1964-1969" and event programs
- Correspondence, 1952-2002, undated; Series IV; 4.17; (10 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of unidentified correspondence and correspondence regarding a 2004 Actors Center Benefit and Richards's retirement is filed at the end of the series.
  Additional correspondence is found in Series I. Production Files; Series II. Professional Papers; and Series III. Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center.
  - "A" general, 1968-1998, undated (Box 131, Folder 1478)
  - Actors' Equity Association, 1952-1965 (Box 131, Folder 1479)
  - Actor's Equity Foundation, Inc., Paul Robinson Award, 1994 (Box 131, Folder 1480)
  - The Africanadian Playwrights' Festival, 1999-2000 (Box 131, Folder 1481)
  - Albertus Magnus College, 1990 (Box 131, Folder 1482)
  - The Algur H. Meadows Award For Excellence in Arts, 1981 (Box 131, Folder 1483)
  - American Film Institute, 1992 (Box 131, Folder 1484)
  - American Theatre Wing, 1994-1995 (Box 131, Folder 1485)
  - Arline Cone Carver Company, 1978 (Box 131, Folder 1486)
  - Audelco, 1986 (Box 131, Folder 1487)
  - "B" general, 1959-1998 (Box 131, Folder 1488)
  - Ballew, Leighton M., 1972 (Box 131, Folder 1489)
  - Bertin, Michael, 1992-1993 (Box 131, Folder 1490)
  - Blessing, Lee, 1988, undated (Box 131, Folder 1491)
  - British Broadcasting Company, 1985 (Box 131, Folder 1492)
  - Bush, George, Sr., 1992 (Box 131, Folder 1493)
  - Bushfire Theatre Award, 1995 (Box 131, Folder 1494)
  - "C" general, 1963-1998 (Box 131, Folder 1495)
  - Cairo International Festival for Experimental Theatre, 1998 (Box 131, Folder 1496)
  - California State University, Honorary Degree at Dominguez Hills, 1993 (Box 131, Folder 1497)
  - Carnegie Melon, 1992 (Box 131, Folder 1498)
  - City College of New York, 1989 (Box 131, Folder 1499)
  - City of New Haven, 1992 (Box 131, Folder 1500)
  - City University of New York, Honorary Degree, 1989-1991 (Box 131, Folder 1501)
  - Columbia University, 1989-1992 (Box 132, Folder 1502)
  - Commonwealth Award, 1985-1988 (Box 132, Folder 1503)
  - Connecticut Artist Award, 1994 (Box 132, Folder 1504)
  - Connecticut College, 1986 (Box 132, Folder 1505)
  - Connecticut Commission Art Award, 1983-1989 (Box 132, Folder 1506)
  - Cornell University, 1990-1992 (Box 132, Folder 1507)
  - Crowley, George Tynan, undated (Box 132, Folder 1508)
  - "D" general, 1970-2002 (Box 132, Folder 1509)
  - Da Silva, 1988-1994 (Box 132, Folder 1510-1511)
  - Danmar, Alan, 1992 (Box 132, Folder 1512)
  - Dallas Theatre Center, 1999 (Box 132, Folder 1513)
  - Dell, Mary, undated (Box 132, Folder 1514)
  - Detroit Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 132, Folder 1515)
  - The Dorothy and Lillian Gish Prize, 2000-2001 (Box 133, Folder 1516-1519)
  - The Drama League, 1992 (Box 133, Folder 1520)
  - Drama Desk Awards, 1993 (Box 133, Folder 1521)
  - Dukore, Bernard, 1972-1973 (Box 133, Folder 1522)
  - "E" general, 1966-1998 (Box 133, Folder 1523)
  - Emery-Ken, Crystal, 1992 (Box 133, Folder 1524)
  - "F" general, 1977-1994, undated (Box 133, Folder 1525)
  - Fugard, Athol, 1982-1986 (Box 133, Folder 1526)
  - "G" general, 1966-1998 (Box 134, Folder 1527)
  - General Artists Corporation, 1961-63 (Box 134, Folder 1528)
  - Golden Plate Awards, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 1529)
  - The Goodman Theatre, 1989-2000 (Box 134, Folder 1530)
  - Governer's Awards, 11th Annual Awards, 1995 (Box 134, Folder 1531)
  - Gurter, Rita M., 1991 (Box 134, Folder 1532)
  - "H" general, 1973-1999 (Box 134, Folder 1533)
  - Harger, Heidi Karolini, undated (Box 134, Folder 1534)
  - Helen Hayes Awards, 1991-1994 (Box 134, Folder 1535)
  - History Makers, 2001-2002 (Box 134, Folder 1536)
  - Hobgood, Burnett, 1996 (Box 134, Folder 1537)
  - Humberston, Lisa L., 1993 (Box 134, Folder 1538)
  - "I" general, 1972 (Box 134, Folder 1539)
  - Ibsen Society of America, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 1540)
  - Isles, Alexandra M., 1991-1993 (Box 134, Folder 1541)
  - "J" general, 1967-1992, undated (Box 134, Folder 1542)
  - John F. Kennedy Center, 1970-1998 (Box 134, Folder 1543)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 134, Folder 1544)
  - Jones, Elroyce, 1992-1993, undated (Box 134, Folder 1545)
    Include photographs
  - "K" general, 197719-94 (Box 134, Folder 1546)
  - Kelly, Raphael, 1969-1970 (Box 134, Folder 1547)
  - Kneff, David S., 1996 (Box 134, Folder 1548)
  - "L" general, 1972-1999, undated (Box 134, Folder 1549)
  - Langsam, Gertrude, 1987-1988 (Box 134, Folder 1550)
  - Last Frontier Conference, 2001 (Box 135, Folder 1551)
  - Leuchtenmuller, Thomas, 1992 (Box 135, Folder 1552)
  - "M" general, 1975-1999, undated (Box 135, Folder 1553)
  - Manhattan Country School, 1993-1994 (Box 135, Folder 1554)
  - Manhattanville College, Honorary Degree, 1995 (Box 135, Folder 1555)
  - Market Theatre Foundation, 1991-1994 (Box 135, Folder 1556)
  - Marsue, undated (Box 135, Folder 1557)
  - McNally, Ellen, 1989 (Box 135, Folder 1558)
  - Mercy College, 1990 (Box 135, Folder 1559)
  - Ming Cho Lee, 1993 (Box 135, Folder 1560)
  - Missouri Arts Council, 1977 (Box 135, Folder 1561)
  - Moore, David, 1988-1990, undated (Box 135, Folder 1562)
  - Moss & Kalish, 1994-1995 (Box 135, Folder 1563)
  - "N" general, 1963-1993 (Box 135, Folder 1564)
  - NAACP, 1993 (Box 135, Folder 1565)
  - National Medal, 1993 (Box 135, Folder 1566-1569)
  - National Theatre of the Deaf, 1978 (Box 135, Folder 1570)
  - Nemiroff Family, 1991 (Box 135, Folder 1571)
  - New England Theatre Conference, 1972-1991 (Box 136, Folder 1572)
  - New Drama Forum Association, Inc., 1977 (Box 136, Folder 1573)
  - New Federal Theatre, 20o0-2001 (Box 136, Folder 1574)
  - New Haven Arts Award, 1983 (Box 136, Folder 1575)
  - New Haven Honors, 1991 (Box 136, Folder 1576)
  - New Tradition. Non-traditional Casting Project, 1993 (Box 136, Folder 1577)
  - New York Urban League, 1986-1987 (Box 136, Folder 1578)
  - Northwestern University, 1993-1995 (Box 136, Folder 1579-1581)
  - "O" general, 1973-1988 (Box 136, Folder 1582)
  - Ohio State University, 1993 (Box 136, Folder 1583)
  - Ohio University, 1992-1993 (Box 136, Folder 1584)
  - Old Settler- Russia, undated (Box 136, Folder 1585)
  - O'Morrison, Kevin, 1988 (Box 136, Folder 1586)
  - "P" general, 1967-1998, undated (Box 136, Folder 1587)
  - Partlan, William, 1996-1997 (Box 136, Folder 1588)
  - Penn State University, 1999 (Box 136, Folder 1589)
  - Philadelphia Festival Theatre For New Plays, 1992-1993 (Box 136, Folder 1590)
  - Phillips Exeter Academy, 1998-1999 (Box 136, Folder 1591)
  - Players (tribute to Lloyd Richards), 2001 (Box 136, Folder 1592)
  - Prince George's Community College, 1992 (Box 136, Folder 1593)
  - "Q" general, 1988 (Box 136, Folder 1594)
  - "R" general, 1972-1999, undated (Box 136, Folder 1595)
  - Rhode Island University, 1968 (Box 136, Folder 1596)
  - Richards family, 1997-1999 (Box 136, Folder 1597)
  - Rollins College, 1987-1988 (Box 136, Folder 1598)
  - "S" general, 1956-2002 (Box 136, Folder 1599)
  - Samuel French, Inc., 1989 (Box 137, Folder 1600)
  - Seasoned Citizens Theatre Company, Inc., 2002 (Box 137, Folder 1601)
  - Shanley, John Patrick, 1988-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1602)
  - Simpson, Jim, 1992, undated (Box 137, Folder 1603)
  - Sklar, Roberta, undated (Box 137, Folder 1604)
  - Solo, 1992 (Box 137, Folder 1605)
  - Some Rain, 1982 (Box 137, Folder 1606)
  - Society of Stage Directors & Choreographers, 1985 (Box 137, Folder 1607)
  - Stage Managers' Association, 1992 (Box 137, Folder 1608)
  - Stefanova-Peteva, Kalina, 1992 (Box 137, Folder 1609)
  - Steinhardt, David, 2001 (Box 137, Folder 1610)
    Include Steinhardt's script for The New Priests Play
  - Stella Adler Conservatory of Acting, 1993-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1611)
  - Susan Smith Blackburn Prize, 1991-1992 (Box 137, Folder 1612)
  - Suther, Richard, 1969 (Box 137, Folder 1613)
  - "T" general, 1966-1998 (Box 137, Folder 1614)
  - Talawa Theatre Company, 1993 (Box 137, Folder 1615)
  - Theatre Communications Group, Inc and American Arts Alliance, 1992 (Box 137, Folder 1616)
  - Theatre Hall of Fame, 1986 (Box 137, Folder 1617)
  - Torch of Hope, 1988 (Box 137, Folder 1618)
  - Toronto's International Theatre Festival, 1998 (Box 137, Folder 1619)
  - Trinity Repertory Company, 1998 (Box 137, Folder 1620)
  - "U" general, 1970-1988 (Box 137, Folder 1621)
  - United States Information Agency, 1993 (Box 137, Folder 1622)
  - University of California, 1991-1992 (Box 137, Folder 1623)
  - University of Detroit, 1990-1991 (Box 137, Folder 1624)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1993-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1625)
  - University of North Carolina, 1974-1978 (Box 137, Folder 1626)
  - Urban Stages, 2002 (Box 137, Folder 1627)
  - "V" general, 1991-1999, undated (Box 137, Folder 1628)
  - "W" general, 1972-1999 (Box 137, Folder 1629)
  - Wayne State University, 1981 (Box 138, Folder 1630)
  - Webster University, 1992 (Box 138, Folder 1631)
  - White family, 1986 (Box 138, Folder 1632)
  - Whitney, Helen, 1992-1993 (Box 138, Folder 1633)
  - Wilson, August, 1984-1987, undated (Box 138, Folder 1634)
  - Witter, Terry, 1986-1988 (Box 138, Folder 1635)
  - WMNR Fine Arts, 1987-1991 (Box 138, Folder 1636)
  - White House, 1988-1993 (Box 138, Folder 1637)
  - Williams College, 1991-1992 (Box 138, Folder 1638)
  - Wright, Doug, 1992-1993 (Box 138, Folder 1639)
  - Writers' Guild, 1986 (Box 138, Folder 1640)
  - "Y" general, 1976-1994 (Box 138, Folder 1641)
  - Yale University, 1987-1994 (Box 138, Folder 1642)
  - "Z" general, undated (Box 138, Folder 1643)
  - Zora Neale Hurston National Museum of Fine Arts, 2002 (Box 138, Folder 1644)
  - Unidentified (Box 138, Folder 1645)
  - "People to remember", 1991-1994 (Box 138, Folder 1646)
  - "Letters of recommendation", 1993-2001 (Box 138, Folder 1647)
  - Correspondence regarding
    - The Actors Center Benefit, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1647a)
      Contains correspondence compiled by various individuals for presentation to Richards on the occasion of The Actors Center Benefit event
    - Retirement, 1991, 1999 (Box 139, Folder 1648-1650)
    - Retirement, 1991, 1999 (Box 140, Folder 1651)
    - Birthday and other cards, 1999-2001, undated (Box 140, Folder 1652-1655)
- Photographs, 1945-2004; Series V; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series V. Photographs is organized into four subseries: Photographs of Lloyd Richards, Productions, Awards and Honorary Degrees, and Photographs of Others.
  This series contains photographs and negatives of Richards, his family, friends and colleagues, productions, events, places, and a small number of unidentified images. Photographs of Richards include snapshots and formal portraits. All negatives have accompanying prints.
  Additional photographs can be found in Series III. Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center.
  - Photographs of Lloyd Richards
    - U.S. Army Corps photographs, 1945 (Box 141, Folder 1656)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha House, Wayne University, Detroit, undated (Box 141, Folder 1657)
      Also includes Paul Robeson
    - "Actors Studio Drama School Class 2004" (Box 141, Folder 1658)
    - With Barbara Davenport Richards, 1987 November (Box 141, Folder 1659)
    - "Disc Jockey, Detroit MI", 1947 (Box 141, Folder 1660)
    - With Athol Fugard, 1984, 1987 (Box 141, Folder 1661-1662)
      Includes photographs of Fugard at Yale Repertory Theatre and slides
    - With James Earl Jones by Ian Calderon, 1979